<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technical on Duing Dev</title>
    <link>https://duing.dev/tags/technical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technical on Duing Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://duing.dev/tags/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Masters?</title>
      <link>https://duing.dev/posts/masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duing.dev/posts/masters/</guid>
      <description>Starting in March, I will start a master&amp;rsquo;s program at University of Brasília, the same university where I graduated almost a year ago. The thought process that I went in order to make such a decision is not conventional and I think it is worth sharing it.
Software Industry As we know, the software industry values academic achievements only in very specific situations, usually involving big companies with very complicated projects to push, such as the next Apple M3 processor and Windows 12 at Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Recursion</title>
      <link>https://duing.dev/posts/fixingrecursion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duing.dev/posts/fixingrecursion/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer I created this post during the make of my graduation project more than one and half years ago. This post served as training of a topic I had the intention of talking about in the final thesis &amp;ndash; something that ended up not happening. You know that when math comes into programming something special is going to happen!
Introduction Recursion is a common way to solve a wide range of problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular Programming or Corecursion</title>
      <link>https://duing.dev/posts/circularprogramming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duing.dev/posts/circularprogramming/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer I created this post during the make of my graduation project more than one and half years ago. This post served as training of a topic I had the intention of talking about in the final thesis &amp;ndash; something that ended up not happening. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a presentation on Dr.Nekoma about the topic, given how interesting it is. The following is the original post.
Introduction Here I present a very descriptive explanation of a solution to a simple example problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
